<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Backgrounds</name>
    <description>Backgrounds for SW-MSV-Edition.</description>
    <update version="2.0.2">
      <file name="backgrounds.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MrBlu03/SW-MSV-EDITION/main/backgrounds.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <!-- AGENT BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Agent" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_AGENT">
    <description>
      <p>You are a covert operative working for a government, military, or private organization. You have been trained in the arts of espionage, infiltration, and information gathering.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Investigation, Persuasion, Stealth</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A badge or emblem from your faction, a set of fine clothes, a disguise kit, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FACTION_CONTACT" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Investigation, Persuasion, Stealth, 2 Languages</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Agent)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Agent)" number="2" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FACTION_CONTACT" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I idolize a particular hero of my faction, and constantly refer to that person's deeds and example.</item>
        <item id="2">I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.</item>
        <item id="3">I see omens in every event and action.</item>
        <item id="4">Nothing can shake my optimistic attitude.</item>
        <item id="5">I quote (or misquote) sacred texts and proverbs in almost every situation.</item>
        <item id="6">I am tolerant (or intolerant) of other factions and respect (or condemn) them.</item>
        <item id="7">I've enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society among my faction's elite. Rough living grates on me.</item>
        <item id="8">I have little practical experience dealing with people in the world.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Charity. I always try to help those in need, no matter what the personal cost. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Change. We must help bring about the changes the gods are constantly working in the world. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Power. I hope to one day rise to the top of my faith's religious hierarchy. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Faith. I trust that my leader will guide my actions, I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy of my leader's favor by matching my actions against his or her teachings. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I would die to recover an artifact of my faction that was lost long ago.</item>
        <item id="2">I will someday get revenge on the corrupt faction hierarchy who branded me a heretic.</item>
        <item id="3">I owe my life to the faction member who took me in when my parents died.</item>
        <item id="4">Everything I do is for the common people.</item>
        <item id="5">I will do anything to protect the faction where I served.</item>
        <item id="6">I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies consider heretical and seek to destroy.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.</item>
        <item id="2">I put too much trust in those who wield power within my faction's hierarchy.</item>
        <item id="3">My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess faith in my faction.</item>
        <item id="4">I am inflexible in my thinking.</item>
        <item id="5">I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.</item>
        <item id="6">Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Faction Contact" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FACTION_CONTACT">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have a contact within your faction who can provide you with information and assistance. This contact can help you gather intelligence, provide safe houses, or supply you with equipment.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Faction Contact" />
  </element>

  <!-- BOUNTY HUNTER BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Bounty Hunter" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_BOUNTY_HUNTER">
    <description>
      <p>You are a professional tracker and hunter of people. Whether you work within the bounds of the law or outside them, you have made a career of finding those who don't want to be found.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Insight, Persuasion, Perception</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Slicing kit</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of manacles, a helmet with a built-in scanner, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 200 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_WANTED_POSTER" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Insight, Persuasion, Perception, Slicing Kit, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Bounty Hunter)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_SLICING_KIT" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Bounty Hunter)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_WANTED_POSTER" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong.</item>
        <item id="2">I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let my emotions control me.</item>
        <item id="3">The first thing I do in a new place is note the locations of everything valuable or where such things could be hidden.</item>
        <item id="4">I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.</item>
        <item id="5">I am incredibly slow to trust. Those who seem the fairest often have the most to hide.</item>
        <item id="6">I don't pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds.</item>
        <item id="7">The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.</item>
        <item id="8">I blow up at the slightest insult.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Honor. I don't steal from others in the trade. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Freedom. Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Charity. I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can jog on for all I care. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.</item>
        <item id="2">My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.</item>
        <item id="3">Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back.</item>
        <item id="4">I will become the greatest thief that ever lived.</item>
        <item id="5">I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.</item>
        <item id="6">Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">When I see something valuable, I can't think about anything but how to steal it.</item>
        <item id="2">When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.</item>
        <item id="3">If there's a plan, I'll forget it. If I don't forget it, I'll ignore it.</item>
        <item id="4">I have a tell that reveals when I'm lying.</item>
        <item id="5">I turn tail and run when things look bad.</item>
        <item id="6">An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I'm okay with that.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Wanted Poster" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_WANTED_POSTER">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have access to a network of informants and can find information about most wanted individuals. You can spend time in populated areas to gather information about bounties.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Wanted Poster" />
  </element>

  <!-- CRIMINAL BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Criminal" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_CRIMINAL">
    <description>
      <p>You are an experienced criminal with a history of breaking the law. You have spent a lot of time among other criminals and still have contacts within the criminal underworld.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Intimidation, Sleight of Hand, Stealth</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Slicing kit</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A slicing kit, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CRIMINAL_CONTACT" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Intimidation, Sleight of Hand, Stealth, Slicing Kit</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Criminal)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_SLICING_KIT" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CRIMINAL_CONTACT" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I always have a plan for what to do when things go wrong.</item>
        <item id="2">I am always calm, no matter what the situation. I never raise my voice or let my emotions control me.</item>
        <item id="3">The first thing I do in a new place is note the locations of everything valuable or where such things could be hidden.</item>
        <item id="4">I would rather make a new friend than a new enemy.</item>
        <item id="5">I am incredibly slow to trust. Those who seem the fairest often have the most to hide.</item>
        <item id="6">I don't pay attention to the risks in a situation. Never tell me the odds.</item>
        <item id="7">The best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.</item>
        <item id="8">I blow up at the slightest insult.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Honor. I don't steal from others in the trade. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Freedom. Chains are meant to be broken, as are those who would forge them. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Charity. I steal from the wealthy so that I can help people in need. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Greed. I will do whatever it takes to become wealthy. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideals, and everyone else can take a trip down the Styx for all I care. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Redemption. There's a spark of good in everyone. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I'm trying to pay off an old debt I owe to a generous benefactor.</item>
        <item id="2">My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.</item>
        <item id="3">Something important was taken from me, and I aim to steal it back.</item>
        <item id="4">I will become the greatest thief that ever lived.</item>
        <item id="5">I'm guilty of a terrible crime. I hope I can redeem myself for it.</item>
        <item id="6">Someone I loved died because of a mistake I made. That will never happen again.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">When I see something valuable, I can't think about anything but how to steal it.</item>
        <item id="2">When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.</item>
        <item id="3">If there's a plan, I'll forget it. If I don't forget it, I'll ignore it.</item>
        <item id="4">I have a tell that reveals when I'm lying.</item>
        <item id="5">I turn tail and run when things look bad.</item>
        <item id="6">An innocent person is in prison for a crime that I committed. I'm okay with that.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Criminal Contact" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CRIMINAL_CONTACT">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other criminals. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Criminal Contact" />
  </element>

  <!-- ENTERTAINER BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Entertainer" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_ENTERTAINER">
    <description>
      <p>You thrive in front of an audience. You know how to entrance them, entertain them, and even inspire them.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Acrobatics, Insight, Performance, Sleight of Hand</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of musical instrument</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A musical instrument (one of your choice), the favor of an admirer (love letter, lock of hair, or trinket), a costume, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BY_POPULAR_DEMAND" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Acrobatics, Insight, Performance, Sleight of Hand, Musical Instrument</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Entertainer)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (Entertainer)" supports="Musical Instrument" number="1" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BY_POPULAR_DEMAND" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I know a story relevant to almost every situation.</item>
        <item id="2">Whenever I come to a new place, I collect local rumors and spread gossip.</item>
        <item id="3">I'm a hopeless romantic, always searching for that special someone.</item>
        <item id="4">Nobody stays angry at me or around me for long, since I can defuse any amount of tension.</item>
        <item id="5">I love a good insult, even one directed at me.</item>
        <item id="6">I get bitter if I'm not the center of attention.</item>
        <item id="7">I'll settle for nothing less than perfection.</item>
        <item id="8">I change my mood or my mind as quickly as I change key in a song.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Beauty. When I perform, I make the world better than it was. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Tradition. The stories, legends, and songs of the past must never be forgotten, for they teach us who we are. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Creativity. The world is in need of new ideas and bold action. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">People. I like seeing the smiles on people's faces when I perform. That's all that matters. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Honesty. Art should reflect the soul; it should come from within and reveal who we really are. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">My instrument is my most treasured possession, and it reminds me of someone I love.</item>
        <item id="2">Someone stole my precious instrument, and someday I'll get it back.</item>
        <item id="3">I want to be famous, whatever it takes.</item>
        <item id="4">I idolize a hero of the old tales and measure my deeds against that person's.</item>
        <item id="5">I will do anything to prove myself superior to my hated rival.</item>
        <item id="6">I would do anything for the other members of my old troupe.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I'll do anything to win fame and renown.</item>
        <item id="2">I'm a sucker for a pretty face.</item>
        <item id="3">A scandal prevents me from ever going home again. That kind of trouble seems to follow me around.</item>
        <item id="4">I once satirized a noble who still wants my head. It was a mistake that I will likely repeat.</item>
        <item id="5">I have trouble keeping my true feelings hidden. My sharp tongue lands me in trouble.</item>
        <item id="6">Despite my best efforts, I am unreliable to my friends.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: By Popular Demand" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BY_POPULAR_DEMAND">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You can always find a place to perform, usually in an inn or tavern but possibly with a circus, at a theater, or even in a noble's court. At such a place, you receive free lodging and food of a modest or comfortable standard.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="By Popular Demand" />
  </element>

  <!-- ENGINEER BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Engineer" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_ENGINEER">
    <description>
      <p>You are a skilled technician and inventor, trained in the repair and modification of machinery, electronics, and droids.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Investigation, Sleight of Hand, Athletics, History</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Repair kit</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A repair kit, a set of common clothes, a technical manual, a set of precision tools, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TINKERER" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Investigation, Sleight of Hand, Athletics, History, Repair Kit</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Engineer)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_REPAIR_KIT" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TINKERER" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I look up to a renowned engineer in my field, and often talk about their work.</item>
        <item id="2">I constantly compare my current situation to my past experiments, many of which went terrifyingly wrong.</item>
        <item id="3">I believe scientific results always comes first.</item>
        <item id="4">I only speak in short incomplete and concise sentences, as they are optimized for efficient communication.</item>
        <item id="5">I often get lost in my own thoughts and contemplation, becoming oblivious to my surroundings.</item>
        <item id="6">I am unable to think logically under great stress, and begin to shout random scientific words.</item>
        <item id="7">I do not believe in etiquette and disregard social expectations.</item>
        <item id="8">I was, in fact, grown and raised in a laboratory.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Transparency. All discoveries should be open to everyone. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Logic. Emotions must not cloud our sense of what is right and true, or our logical thinking. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Free Thinking. Inquiry and curiosity are the pillars of progress. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">My research is also my best companion.</item>
        <item id="2">I will get revenge on the criminals that stole my research.</item>
        <item id="3">The school I studied at is the most important place in the world to me.</item>
        <item id="4">One day I will return to my home planet and prove that I am the greatest scientist of them all.</item>
        <item id="5">I believe my research will be the key to saving the life of a loved one.</item>
        <item id="6">I owe my instructor a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I believe only other scientists deserve my respect.</item>
        <item id="2">I fail to understand why people don't understand my technical jargon.</item>
        <item id="3">I experiment on myself without thinking about the long term consequences.</item>
        <item id="4">I am paranoid that people are out to steal my research.</item>
        <item id="5">I believe I work better when under the influence of intoxicants.</item>
        <item id="6">I work on my research to the point where I ignore my own bodily needs.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Tinkerer" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_TINKERER">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have an intuitive understanding of how mechanical and electronic devices work. Given sufficient time and materials, you can repair most damaged equipment or create simple devices.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Tinkerer" />
  </element>

  <!-- JEDI BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Jedi" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_JEDI">
    <description>
      <p>You have spent your life studying the ways of the Force and the teachings of the Jedi Order.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Insight, Investigation, History, Persuasion, Arcana</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of Jedi robes, a holocron containing Jedi teachings, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_JEDI_CODE_KNOWLEDGE" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Insight, Investigation, History, Persuasion, Arcana, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Jedi)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Jedi)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_JEDI_CODE_KNOWLEDGE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I idolize a particular Jedi, and constantly refer to that person's deeds and example.</item>
        <item id="2">I can find common ground between the fiercest enemies, empathizing with them and always working towards peace.</item>
        <item id="3">I see omens in every event and action. The Force tries to speak to us, we just need to listen</item>
        <item id="4">Nothing can shake my optimistic attitude.</item>
        <item id="5">I quote (or misquote) sacred Jedi texts and proverbs in almost every situation.</item>
        <item id="6">I am tolerant (or intolerant) of those who don't support the Jedi.</item>
        <item id="7">I've enjoyed fine food, drink, and high society. Rough living grates on me.</item>
        <item id="8">I've spent so long in the Jedi temple that I have little practical experience dealing with people in the world.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Tradition. The ancient traditions of worship and sacrifice must be preserved and upheld. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Charity. I always try to help those in need, no matter what the personal cost. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Change. We must help bring about the changes the Force is constantly working in the world. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Power. I hope to one day rise to the rank of Jedi Master. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Faith. I trust that the Force will guide my actions; I have faith that if I work hard, things will go well. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I seek to prove myself worthy of the Force by matching my actions against the Jedi teachings. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I would die to recover an ancient Jedi relic that was lost long ago.</item>
        <item id="2">I will someday get revenge on those who razed my temple.</item>
        <item id="3">I owe my life to the Jedi who took me in when my parents died.</item>
        <item id="4">Everything I do is for the common people.</item>
        <item id="5">I will do anything to protect the temple where I served.</item>
        <item id="6">I seek to preserve a sacred text that my enemies seek to destroy.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I judge others harshly, and myself even more severely.</item>
        <item id="2">I put too much trust in those who wield power within my temple's hierarchy.</item>
        <item id="3">My piety sometimes leads me to blindly trust those that profess faith in the Force.</item>
        <item id="4">I am inflexible in my thinking.</item>
        <item id="5">I am suspicious of strangers and expect the worst of them.</item>
        <item id="6">Once I pick a goal, I become obsessed with it to the detriment of everything else in my life.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Jedi Code Knowledge" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_JEDI_CODE_KNOWLEDGE">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You know the Jedi Code by heart: There is no emotion, there is peace. There is no ignorance, there is knowledge. There is no passion, there is serenity. There is no chaos, there is harmony. There is no death, there is the Force.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Jedi Code Knowledge" />
  </element>

  <!-- MANDALORIAN BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Mandalorian" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_MANDALORIAN">
    <description>
      <p>You were raised in the warrior culture of Mandalore, bound by the Resol'nare - the six actions that define what it means to be Mandalorian.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Athletics, Intimidation, Survival, History</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Hover pack</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> Mando'a</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A suit of Mandalorian armor, a clan sigil, a hover pack, and a belt pouch containing 200 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_CONNECTION" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Athletics, Intimidation, Survival, History, Hover Pack, Mando'a</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Mandalorian)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Mandalorian Clan" supports="Mandalorian Clan" number="1" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_MSV_LANGUAGE_MANDOA" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_HOVERPACK" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_CONNECTION" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I try and bring my culture to outsiders.</item>
        <item id="2">I always put my clan first.</item>
        <item id="3">I follow the Resol'nare to the letter.</item>
        <item id="4">I love a good spar.</item>
        <item id="5">I enjoy traveling the galaxy.</item>
        <item id="6">I keep a small trophy on me to remind me of a past victory.</item>
        <item id="7">I view the force as dishonorable in combat.</item>
        <item id="8">I've seen the horrors of battle and try to prevent it.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Tradition. I live by my clan's ways, and will continue to do so. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Power. I strive to be the best warrior, no matter who stands in my way. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Respect. I have earned the respect of many, and I intend to keep it. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Freedom. I enjoy having the ability to do whatever I want. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Comradery. I'll put everything on the line for those dear to me. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I'll succeed in my goals, it just takes time and effort. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I lost someone dear to me in battle, I will always honor them.</item>
        <item id="2">Honor is everything to me.</item>
        <item id="3">I will lay down my life for those beside me.</item>
        <item id="4">I must keep the traditions of my ancestors alive.</item>
        <item id="5">No matter where I go, Mandalore is my home.</item>
        <item id="6">In death, I will find glory.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I look down on outsiders.</item>
        <item id="2">I have no respect for anyone who flees. Cowardice is unacceptable.</item>
        <item id="3">I don't see much use in talking, a blaster is all I need to make my point.</item>
        <item id="4">I stick to my traditions no matter what, even at the cost of others.</item>
        <item id="5">I retreated once, and I've regretted it ever since.</item>
        <item id="6">I value a victory regardless of the ethics behind the victory.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Clan Connection" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_CONNECTION">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You can always find a place to stay and resupply among other Mandalorians, provided you adhere to the Resol'nare. Other Mandalorians will recognize you as one of their own and offer you hospitality.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Connection" />
  </element>

  <!-- MERCENARY BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Mercenary" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_MERCENARY">
    <description>
      <p>You are a soldier for hire, selling your combat skills to the highest bidder. You've fought in countless conflicts across the galaxy.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Athletics, Investigation, Deception, Intimidation</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A uniform from your last mercenary company, a trophy from a past battle, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MERCENARY_CONTRACT" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Athletics, Investigation, Deception, Intimidation, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Mercenary)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Mercenary)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MERCENARY_CONTRACT" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I do not fear death, but accept it as part of life.</item>
        <item id="2">I have a crude sense of humor.</item>
        <item id="3">I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.</item>
        <item id="4">I find it good luck to have a flask of ale on me even when the most of my other belongings are gone.</item>
        <item id="5">I ask a lot of questions.</item>
        <item id="6">I never pass up a friendly wager.</item>
        <item id="7">I am always polite and respectful when speaking to those above my station.</item>
        <item id="8">I like a job well done, especially if I'm not the one doing it.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Greed. I'm only doing it for the money. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Fairness. We all did the work. it is only right that everyone gets a share of the reward. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Live and Let Live. You may not have a family left, but your enemy may. A little compassion goes a long way. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Measure of Last Resort. Sometimes we have to do things that we REALLY don't want to do, but we must remember that we only do them because we have to. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Debts. I never leave a favor left undone and nor will I leave those whom owe me favors on the hook. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I have heard a tale of a legendary person of my class. I strive to be more like them. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I have a personal debt that must be paid.</item>
        <item id="2">I am with friends whom I trust with my life as they should trust me with theirs.</item>
        <item id="3">I come from a family that dislikes weaknesses, so I push myself to know my weaknesses.</item>
        <item id="4">My life is my honor. I shall, until death, shape my life to what I want it to be.</item>
        <item id="5">Without a purpose in the world, I find myself to be broken which I do not like.</item>
        <item id="6">I secretly pursue a love interest that is forbidden by a family whether it is my own or my love's family.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I am always looking for the bigger pay.</item>
        <item id="2">I can't tell a lie for the life of me.</item>
        <item id="3">I judge too easily by special appearance and pride.</item>
        <item id="4">I am almost always carrying some ale in with my gear.</item>
        <item id="5">I believe that I am the only skilled person of the group and am even open about it.</item>
        <item id="6">I will never let a comrade stand alone, even if it gets me killed.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Mercenary Contract" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MERCENARY_CONTRACT">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have connections with various mercenary companies and can find work as a hired soldier relatively easily. When in civilized areas, you can find information about upcoming conflicts and potential employers.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Mercenary Contract" />
  </element>

  <!-- NOBLE BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Noble" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_NOBLE">
    <description>
      <p>You understand wealth, power, and privilege. You carry a noble title, and your family owns land, collects taxes, and wields significant political influence.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Insight, History, Persuasion</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of fine clothes, a signet ring, a scroll of pedigree, and a purse containing 250 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_POSITION_OF_PRIVILEGE" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Insight, History, Persuasion, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Noble)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Noble)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_POSITION_OF_PRIVILEGE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">My eloquent flattery makes everyone I talk to feel like the most wonderful and important person in the world.</item>
        <item id="2">The common folk love me for my kindness and generosity.</item>
        <item id="3">No one could doubt by looking at my regal bearing that I am a cut above the unwashed masses.</item>
        <item id="4">I take great pains to always look my best and follow the latest fashions.</item>
        <item id="5">I don't like to get my hands dirty, and I won't be caught dead in unsuitable accommodations.</item>
        <item id="6">Despite my noble birth, I do not place myself above other folk. We all have the same blood.</item>
        <item id="7">My favor, once lost, is lost forever.</item>
        <item id="8">If you do me an injury, I will crush you, ruin your name, and salt your fields.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Respect. Respect is due to me because of my position, but all people regardless of station deserve to be treated with dignity. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Responsibility. It is my duty to respect the authority of those above me, just as those below me must respect mine. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Independence. I must prove that I can handle myself without the coddling of my family. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Power. If I can attain more power, no one will tell me what to do. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Family. Blood runs thicker than water. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Noble Obligation. It is my duty to protect and care for the people beneath me. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I will face any challenge to win the approval of my family.</item>
        <item id="2">My house's alliance with another noble family must be sustained at all costs.</item>
        <item id="3">Nothing is more important than the other members of my family.</item>
        <item id="4">I am in love with the heir of a family that my family despises.</item>
        <item id="5">My loyalty to my sovereign is unwavering.</item>
        <item id="6">The common folk must see me as a hero of the people.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I secretly believe that everyone is beneath me.</item>
        <item id="2">I hide a truly scandalous secret that could ruin my family forever.</item>
        <item id="3">I too often hear veiled insults and threats in every word addressed to me, and I'm quick to anger.</item>
        <item id="4">I have an insatiable desire for carnal pleasures.</item>
        <item id="5">In fact, the world does revolve around me.</item>
        <item id="6">By my words and actions, I often bring shame to my family.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Position of Privilege" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_POSITION_OF_PRIVILEGE">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Thanks to your noble birth, people are inclined to think the best of you. You are welcome in high society, and people assume you have the right to be wherever you are. The common folk make every effort to accommodate you and avoid your displeasure, and other people of high birth treat you as a member of the same social sphere. You can secure an audience with a local noble if you need to.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Position of Privilege" />
  </element>

  <!-- NOMAD BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Nomad" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_NOMAD">
    <description>
      <p>You have traveled the galaxy, never staying in one place for long. You have learned to survive in harsh environments and adapt to new cultures.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Survival, Medicine</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of musical instrument</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A musical instrument, a trophy from an animal you hunted, a set of traveler's clothes, and a belt pouch containing 100 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_WANDERER" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Animal Handling, Athletics, Survival, Medicine, Musical Instrument, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Nomad)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (Nomad)" supports="Musical Instrument" number="1" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Nomad)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_WANDERER" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I'm driven by a wanderlust that led me away from home.</item>
        <item id="2">I watch over my friends as if they were a litter of newborn pups.</item>
        <item id="3">I once ran twenty-five miles without stopping to warn my clan of an approaching horde. I'd do it again if I had to.</item>
        <item id="4">I have a lesson for every situation, drawn from observing nature.</item>
        <item id="5">I place no stock in wealthy or well-mannered folk. Money and manners won't save you from a hungry rancor.</item>
        <item id="6">I'm always picking things up, absently fiddling with them, and sometimes accidentally breaking them.</item>
        <item id="7">I feel far more comfortable around animals than people.</item>
        <item id="8">I was, in fact, raised by wampas.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Change. Life is like the seasons, in constant change, and we must change with it. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Greater Good. It is each person's responsibility to make the most happiness for the whole tribe. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Honor. If I dishonor myself, I dishonor my whole clan. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Might. The strongest are meant to rule. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Nature. The natural world is more important than all the constructs of civilization. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Glory. I must earn glory in battle, for myself and my clan. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">My family, clan, or tribe is the most important thing in my life, even when they are far from me.</item>
        <item id="2">An injury to the unspoiled wilderness of my home is an injury to me.</item>
        <item id="3">I will bring terrible wrath down on the Darkdoers who destroyed my homeland.</item>
        <item id="4">I am the last of my tribe, and it is up to me to ensure their names enter legend.</item>
        <item id="5">I suffer awful visions of a coming disaster and will do anything to prevent it.</item>
        <item id="6">It is my duty to provide children to sustain my tribe.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I am too enamored of ale, wine, and other intoxicants.</item>
        <item id="2">There's no room for caution in a life lived to the fullest.</item>
        <item id="3">I remember every insult I've received and nurse a silent resentment toward anyone who's ever wronged me.</item>
        <item id="4">I am slow to trust members of other species, tribes, and societies.</item>
        <item id="5">Violence is my answer to almost any challenge.</item>
        <item id="6">Don't expect me to save those who can't save themselves. It is nature's way that the strong thrive and the weak perish.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Wanderer" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_WANDERER">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have an excellent memory for maps and geography, and you can always recall the general layout of terrain, settlements, and other features around you. In addition, you can find food and fresh water for yourself and up to five other people each day, provided that the land offers berries, small game, water, and so forth.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Wanderer" />
  </element>

  <!-- PIRATE BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Pirate" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_PIRATE">
    <description>
      <p>You spent your youth under the sway of a dreaded pirate, learning how to survive in a world of sharks and cutthroats. You may have been a sailor on a starship, a pilot in a fighter squadron, or part of a pirate crew raiding cargo vessels.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Athletics, Deception, Intimidation, Sleight of Hand</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Slicing kit</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A slicing kit, a set of common clothes, a piece of jewelry worth 100 credits, and a belt pouch containing 50 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SHIP_PASSAGE" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Athletics, Deception, Intimidation, Sleight of Hand, Slicing Kit</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Pirate)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_SLICING_KIT" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SHIP_PASSAGE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I respect my captain and trust my crew. It may be all that saves my life one day.</item>
        <item id="2">Whether the credits comes from the split of the spoils or from a side wager, I'll get my hands on it.</item>
        <item id="3">When my blood gets up, my swearing could boil the icy tundra of Hoth.</item>
        <item id="4">I enjoy spreading the tales of my exploits, no matter who hears.</item>
        <item id="5">I never let witnesses escape from a raid.</item>
        <item id="6">I take what I need, but I don't kill without reason.</item>
        <item id="7">I always have an exit planned.</item>
        <item id="8">I assume everyone else wants to take what I have.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Equal Shares. All hands who spend sweat and blood earn their share of the credits. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Adventure. I'm far from home, and everything is strange and wonderful! (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Greater Good. I raid to weaken the Empire that threatens my people, but I don't steal from civilians. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Strength. The weak exist to feed the strong, and I am strong. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Crew. A ship is nothing without her crew. Protect your mates. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Ambition. One day I will be so much more than a captain. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">My band and I will be known across the world, and we'll never be forgotten.</item>
        <item id="2">My ill-gotten gains go to support my family.</item>
        <item id="3">Everything I do is for the good of my people.</item>
        <item id="4">My ship and many of her crew were lost to treachery, and I won't rest until I discover who was behind it.</item>
        <item id="5">My ship comes first, and all other loyalties simply pale in comparison.</item>
        <item id="6">A crew member of a ship we raided saved my life, and I don't know how to resolve that debt.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I never back down from a fight.</item>
        <item id="2">When faced with a choice between money and my friends, I usually choose the money.</item>
        <item id="3">I was drunk on watch when my ship was lost to an ambush. I can't set the shame aside.</item>
        <item id="4">I feel I'm entitled to a greater share of the spoils, no matter the circumstances.</item>
        <item id="5">I won't let myself be captured. If a raid goes sour, I'm the first to run for cover.</item>
        <item id="6">I get lost in the thrill of the raid and can't focus on the details of a plan.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Ship's Passage" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SHIP_PASSAGE">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>When you need to, you can secure free passage on a starship for yourself and your adventuring companions. You might sail on the ship you served on, or another ship you have good relations with (perhaps one captained by a former crewmate). Because you're calling in a favor, you can't be certain of a schedule or route that will meet your every need. Your Dungeon Master will determine how long it takes to get where you need to go. In return for your free passage, you and your companions are expected to assist the crew during the voyage.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Ship's Passage" />
  </element>

  <!-- SCIENTIST BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Scientist" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_SCIENTIST">
    <description>
      <p>You have spent years studying the galaxy's mysteries, conducting research, and expanding the boundaries of knowledge. Your expertise may be in biology, physics, astronomy, or any other scientific field.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from History, Medicine, Nature, Investigation</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Slicing kit</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A slicing kit, a datapad, a set of common clothes, a letter from a colleague, and a belt pouch containing 100 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RESEARCHER" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">History, Medicine, Nature, Investigation, Slicing Kit, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Scientist)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_SLICING_KIT" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Scientist)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RESEARCHER" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I look up to a renowned scientist in my field, and often talk about their work.</item>
        <item id="2">I constantly compare my current situation to my past experiments, many of which went terrifyingly wrong.</item>
        <item id="3">I believe scientific results always comes first.</item>
        <item id="4">I only speak in short incomplete and concise sentences, as they are optimized for efficient communication.</item>
        <item id="5">I often get lost in my own thoughts and contemplation, becoming oblivious to my surroundings.</item>
        <item id="6">I am unable to think logically under great stress, and begin to shout random scientific words.</item>
        <item id="7">I do not believe in etiquette and disregard social expectations.</item>
        <item id="8">I was, in fact, grown and raised in a laboratory.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Transparency. All discoveries should be open to everyone. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Logic. Emotions must not cloud our sense of what is right and true, or our logical thinking. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Greed. I'm only in it for the money and fame. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Free Thinking. Inquiry and curiosity are the pillars of progress. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Live and Let Live. Meddling in the affairs of others only causes trouble. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I work hard to be the best there is at my craft. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">My research is also my best companion.</item>
        <item id="2">I will get revenge on the criminals that stole my research.</item>
        <item id="3">The school I studied at is the most important place in the world to me.</item>
        <item id="4">One day I will return to my home planet and prove that I am the greatest scientist of them all.</item>
        <item id="5">I believe my research will be the key to saving the life of a loved one.</item>
        <item id="6">I owe my instructor a great debt for forging me into the person I am today.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I believe only other scientists deserve my respect.</item>
        <item id="2">I fail to understand why people don't understand my technical jargon.</item>
        <item id="3">I experiment on myself without thinking about the long term consequences.</item>
        <item id="4">I am paranoid that people are out to steal my research.</item>
        <item id="5">I believe I work better when under the influence of intoxicants.</item>
        <item id="6">I work on my research to the point where I ignore my own bodily needs.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Researcher" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RESEARCHER">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>When you attempt to learn or recall a piece of knowledge, if you do not know that information, you often know where and from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information comes from a library, research facility, university, or a scholar. Your DM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an almost inaccessible place, or that it simply cannot be found. Unearthing the deepest secrets of the galaxy can require an adventure or even a whole campaign.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Researcher" />
  </element>

  <!-- SCOUNDREL BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Scoundrel" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_SCOUNDREL">
    <description>
      <p>You are a smooth-talking charmer, a gambler, or a silver-tongued negotiator. You know how to get what you want through persuasion, deception, or sheer force of personality.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Insight, Performance, Sleight of Hand</li>
        <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Forgery kit</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A forgery kit, a set of fine clothes, a deck of cards, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FALSE_IDENTITY" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Insight, Performance, Sleight of Hand, Forgery Kit</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Scoundrel)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_MSV_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_FORGERY_KIT" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FALSE_IDENTITY" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I fall in and out of love easily, and am always pursuing someone.</item>
        <item id="2">I have a joke for every occasion, especially occasions where humor is inappropriate.</item>
        <item id="3">Flattery is my preferred trick for getting what I want.</item>
        <item id="4">I'm a born gambler who can't resist taking a risk for a potential payoff.</item>
        <item id="5">I lie about almost everything, even when there's no good reason to.</item>
        <item id="6">Sarcasm and insults are my weapons of choice.</item>
        <item id="7">I keep multiple symbols on me and invoke whatever power might come in useful at any given moment.</item>
        <item id="8">I pocket anything I see that might have some value.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Independence. I am a free spirit no one tells me what to do. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Fairness. I never target people who can't afford to lose a few creds. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Charity. I distribute the money I acquire to the people who really need it. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Creativity. I never run the same con twice. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Friendship. Material goods come and go. Bonds of friendship last forever. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I'm determined to make something of myself. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I fleeced the wrong person and must work to ensure that this individual never crosses paths with me or those I care about.</item>
        <item id="2">I owe everything to my mentor a horrible person who's probably rotting in jail somewhere.</item>
        <item id="3">Somewhere out there, I have a child who doesn't know me. I'm making the world better for him or her.</item>
        <item id="4">I come from a noble family, and one day I'll reclaim my lands and title from those who stole them from me.</item>
        <item id="5">A powerful person killed someone I love. Some day soon, I'll have my revenge.</item>
        <item id="6">I swindled and ruined a person who didn't deserve it, and I seek to atone for my misdeeds.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I can't resist a pretty face.</item>
        <item id="2">I'm always in debt. I spend my ill-gotten gains on decadent luxuries faster than I bring them in.</item>
        <item id="3">I'm convinced that no one could ever fool me the way I fool others.</item>
        <item id="4">I'm too greedy for my own good. I can't resist taking a risk if there's money involved.</item>
        <item id="5">I can't resist swindling people who are more powerful than me.</item>
        <item id="6">I hate to admit it and will hate myself for it, but I'll run and preserve my own hide if the going gets tough.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: False Identity" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FALSE_IDENTITY">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have created a second identity that includes documentation, established acquaintances, and disguises that allow you to assume that persona. Additionally, you can forge documents including official papers and personal letters, as long as you have seen an example of the kind of document or the handwriting you are trying to copy.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="False Identity" />
  </element>

  <!-- SITH BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Sith" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_SITH">
    <description>
      <p>You have been trained in the dark side of the Force, following the ancient traditions of the Sith. You seek power above all else, embracing your passions and emotions to fuel your connection to the Force.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Insight, Intimidation, History, Arcana</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of dark robes, a Sith holocron, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SITH_CODE_KNOWLEDGE" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Insight, Intimidation, History, Arcana, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Sith)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Sith)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SITH_CODE_KNOWLEDGE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I idolize a particular Sith, and constantly refer to that person's deeds and example.</item>
        <item id="2">I seek power above all else.</item>
        <item id="3">I prefer using a lightsaber to solve my problems.</item>
        <item id="4">I have a plan for any situation.</item>
        <item id="5">I believe everyone is beneath me.</item>
        <item id="6">I prefer to let someone else do my dirty work.</item>
        <item id="7">Hatred and anger drive every decision I make.</item>
        <item id="8">Lying and scheming are second nature to me.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Patience. I will defeat my enemies in the end, I'm in no rush. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Disdain. I never try to help those in need, regardless of how simple it would be. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Knowledge. The path to power and self-improvement is through knowledge. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Power. I hope to one day rise to the rank of Dark Lord of the Sith. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Might. If I become strong, I can take what I want what I deserve. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Aspiration. I'll succeed in my goals at any cost. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I would die to recover an ancient Sith relic that was lost long ago.</item>
        <item id="2">I care only about myself.</item>
        <item id="3">I owe my life to the Sith who took me in when my parents died.</item>
        <item id="4">My enemies will be defeated, even if it costs me my life.</item>
        <item id="5">Someone I love was killed. Some day soon, I'll have my revenge.</item>
        <item id="6">My loyalty to my master is unwavering.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">I am too merciful, and empathize with those I shouldn't.</item>
        <item id="2">I put too much trust in those who rule over me.</item>
        <item id="3">I will never fully trust anyone other than myself.</item>
        <item id="4">I am inflexible in my thinking.</item>
        <item id="5">My pride will probably lead to my destruction.</item>
        <item id="6">Failure frightens me, and I get desperate if I think I might fail.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Sith Code Knowledge" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SITH_CODE_KNOWLEDGE">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You know the Sith Code by heart: Peace is a lie, there is only passion. Through passion I gain strength. Through strength I gain power. Through power I gain victory. Through victory my chains are broken. The Force shall free me.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Sith Code Knowledge" />
  </element>

  <!-- SMUGGLER BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Smuggler" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_SMUGGLER">
    <description>
      <p>You have transported illegal goods across borders and past blockades. You know the best routes to avoid detection and how to hide contraband from prying eyes.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Deception, Sleight of Hand, Stealth, Acrobatics</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A set of traveler's clothes, a set of concealed pockets, and a belt pouch containing 150 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SMUGGLER_NETWORK" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Deception, Sleight of Hand, Stealth, Acrobatics</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Smuggler)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SMUGGLER_NETWORK" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I am extremely sociable, especially over a mug of ale.</item>
        <item id="2">I always keep my wares close to me, you never know who might stumble across them otherwise.</item>
        <item id="3">The best way to hide is out in the open.</item>
        <item id="4">I'm a terrible gossip.</item>
        <item id="5">Being seen with any unsavory figures is a sure way to undermine my work, which is why I work out of sight.</item>
        <item id="6">Deflecting questions has become second nature to me, so I rarely answer straight.</item>
        <item id="7">I have dozens of identities and live in constant fear of answering to the wrong name.</item>
        <item id="8">I act irrationally confident in the face of danger, nobody suspects anything when you seem like you're in charge.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Morals. I only smuggle things to improve the lives of the common folk. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Ruthless. I will rise to the top of the heap by any means necessary. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Friendship. My associates are dear to me, and I want them to rise with me when I hit it big. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Dauntless. No border crossing or bribe is too difficult- that's just the coward's way of saying exciting! (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Greater Good. I work for a greater cause, and ply my trade only in service to it. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Unperturbed. I only want to make a living for myself, and smuggling is just an edge I can use to do so. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">A corrupt official shut me down back in my honest days. I aim to show him a thing or two about recovery.</item>
        <item id="2">I never wanted to be a criminal, but it pays the bills.</item>
        <item id="3">A bloodthirsty pirate stole a shipment from me and killed a dear friend of mine. I will have my vengeance.</item>
        <item id="4">Someone I cared about discovered my profession and has publicly denounced me, and I am caught between protecting my reputation and restoring our relationship.</item>
        <item id="5">My love interest is someone who once stole from right under my nose- but they have no idea who I am or how much I admire them for their accomplishment.</item>
        <item id="6">My business partners are closer to me than my family.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">"Trust nobody, not even yourself." I am plagued by paranoia.</item>
        <item id="2">I'm so charismatic that sometimes I woo myself. Who am I, Narcissus?</item>
        <item id="3">Money is my greatest motivator. I'll do almost anything given enough of it, even if I'll regret it later.</item>
        <item id="4">I would betray anyone to save my own skin.</item>
        <item id="5">I detach myself from the results of my actions in order to sleep better at night.</item>
        <item id="6">Someone who knows me well might call me "two-faced" but those who don't have no idea what hit 'em.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Smuggler's Network" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SMUGGLER_NETWORK">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have advantage when bribing officials and can always find a safe house or secret route to move contraband. You know who to talk to and how much to pay to get what you need across borders.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Smuggler's Network" />
  </element>

  <!-- SOLDIER BACKGROUND -->
  <element name="Soldier" type="Background" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_SOLDIER">
    <description>
      <p>War has been your life for as long as you care to remember. You trained as a youth, studied the use of weapons and armor, learned basic survival techniques, including how to stay alive on the battlefield.</p>
      <ul class="unstyled">
        <li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Choose two from Athletics, Intimidation, Persuasion, Investigation</li>
        <li><strong>Languages:</strong> One of your choice</li>
        <li><strong>Equipment:</strong> An insignia of rank, a trophy taken from a fallen enemy, a set of common clothes, 1 plasma grenade, 1 ion grenade, and a belt pouch containing 100 credits</li>
      </ul>
      <div element="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MILITARY_RANK" />
      <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">Athletics, Intimidation, Persuasion, Investigation, 1 Language</set>
    </setters>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Soldier)" number="2" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Soldier)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
      <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MILITARY_RANK" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
      <select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
      <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
        <item id="1">I'm always polite and respectful.</item>
        <item id="2">I'm haunted by memories of war. I can't get the images of violence out of my mind.</item>
        <item id="3">I've lost too many friends, and I'm slow to make new ones.</item>
        <item id="4">I'm full of inspiring and cautionary tales from my military experience relevant to almost every combat situation.</item>
        <item id="5">I can stare down a hell hound without flinching.</item>
        <item id="6">I enjoy being strong and like breaking things.</item>
        <item id="7">I have a crude sense of humor.</item>
        <item id="8">I face problems head-on. A simple, direct solution is the best path to success.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Ideal">
        <item id="1">Greater Good. Our lot is to lay down our lives in defense of others. (Lawful)</item>
        <item id="2">Responsibility. I do what I must and obey just authority. (Good)</item>
        <item id="3">Independence. When people follow orders blindly, they embrace a kind of tyranny. (Chaotic)</item>
        <item id="4">Might. In life as in war, the stronger force wins. (Evil)</item>
        <item id="5">Live and Let Live. Ideals aren't worth killing over or going to war for. (Neutral)</item>
        <item id="6">Nation. My city, nation, or people are all that matter. (Any)</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Bond">
        <item id="1">I would still lay down my life for the people I served with.</item>
        <item id="2">Someone saved my life on the battlefield. To this day, I will never leave a friend behind.</item>
        <item id="3">My honor is my life.</item>
        <item id="4">I'll never forget the crushing defeat my company suffered or the enemies who dealt it.</item>
        <item id="5">Those who fight beside me are those worth dying for.</item>
        <item id="6">I fight for those who cannot fight for themselves.</item>
      </select>
      <select type="List" name="Flaw">
        <item id="1">The monstrous enemy we faced in battle still leaves me quivering with fear.</item>
        <item id="2">I have little respect for anyone who is not a proven warrior.</item>
        <item id="3">I made a terrible mistake in battle cost many lives and I would do anything to keep that mistake secret.</item>
        <item id="4">My hatred of my enemies is blind and unreasoning.</item>
        <item id="5">I obey the law, even if the law causes misery.</item>
        <item id="6">I'd rather eat my armor than admit when I'm wrong.</item>
      </select>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Feature: Military Rank" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_MILITARY_RANK">
    <supports>Background Feature</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have a military rank from your career as a soldier. Soldiers loyal to your former military organization still recognize your authority and influence, and they defer to you if they are of a lower rank. You can invoke your rank to exert influence over other soldiers and requisition simple equipment for temporary use.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Military Rank" />
  </element>

  <!-- MANDALORIAN CLANS -->
  <element name="Clan Vizsla" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_VIZSLA">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You are a member of Clan Vizsla, one of the most ancient and respected Mandalorian clans, known for producing many great leaders and warriors.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Vizsla" />
  </element>

  <element name="Clan Fett" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_FETT">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You are a member of Clan Fett, a clan known for its bounty hunters and mercenaries who have left their mark on galactic history.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Fett" />
  </element>

  <element name="Clan Varad" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_VARAD">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You are a member of Clan Varad, known for their fierce warriors and tactical brilliance in battle.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Varad" />
  </element>

  <element name="Clan Ordo" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_ORDO">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You are a member of Clan Ordo, a clan with a proud military tradition and honor-bound warriors.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Ordo" />
  </element>

  <element name="Clan Lok" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_LOK">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You are a member of Clan Lok, known for their stealth and precision in combat.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Lok" />
  </element>

  <element name="Clan Cadera" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_CADERA">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You are a member of Clan Cadera, a clan that values honor and tradition above all else.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clan Cadera" />
  </element>

  <element name="Clanless" type="Background Feature" source="SW-MSV-Edition" id="ID_SW_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CLAN_CLANLESS">
    <supports>Mandalorian Clan</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have no clan affiliation, either by choice or circumstance. You walk your own path among the Mandalorians.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Clanless" />
  </element>

</elements>
